

GUSTAVO LOBOS

Engineer | Java Developer | Projects | Salesforce

About Me

I' m a seasoned professional with a solid 25-year career in the Oil&Gas Industry, where I have held roles of increasing responsibility in Operations, Projects and Engineering.

My passion for technology led me to acquire strong IT skills, particularly in backend development. With expertise in Java, databases, and proficency in DevOps and AWS, I am well-bersed in agile methodologies and CRM software like Salesforce.

I am excited to explore new opportunities in the field of information technology or project management, where I can contribute to the development of creative and efficient solutions.

Contact Me

- gjlobos141@gmail.com
- +5493489593664
- Ocampana, Buenos Aires Argentina
- in linkedin.com/in/gjlobos/?locale=en_US
- github.com/gjlobos
- https://www.salesforce.com/trailblazer/gjlobos

Oil&Gas Hard Skills

- Distribution Terminals Operation, Maintenance and Design.
- Atmospheric and pressurized tanks Operation
- Docks Operation, Maintenance and Design.
- Management of Change (MOC)
- Process Safety and Risk management (PSM -IRM) - Product Hazard - Aviation Fuels
- Fire Emergency Response system (NFPA)
- Project Management (MS-Project | PM4R Agile)
- Production and Inventory Accounting VMPA
- ISO Internal Auditor (9001 14001)
- Measurements standards (API MPMS)

Languages

Spanish Native

English Full professional proficiency

French Elementary proficiency

Soft Skills

- Teamwork player | Active-listener
- Leadership Empathy and Member Support
- Attention to Details Problem Solver
- Creativity and Innovation
- Excellent Communication (Oral and Written)
- Continuous Learning Flexibility / Adaptability
- Agile Methodologies (Scrum Kanban)

IT Hard Skills

- Backend developer | Java NodeJS Spring
 Boot API Rest Maven Hibernate Microservices Go
- Frontend developer | JS React HTML CSS
- Database | MySQL Workbench MongoDB -PostgreSQL
- Testing | Manual Automated Postman Junit
 RestAssured Selenium
- Infraestructure | AWS (VPC, EC2, S3, RDS)
- DevOps | Linux Terraform Docker K8S
- Git | Github | Gitlab | Trello | Jira | Confluence |
 MS-Project | Slack | Discord | Notion
- Salesforce Admin (Data Modeling and Management, IAM and User Management, Reports and Dashboards, Formulas and Validations, Flows, Process Approvals)
- Salesforce Developer (LWC, Apex, DML, SOQL, SOSL, triggers, Visual Force)
- Power-BI / Excel dashboards and data analysis



GUSTAVO LOBOS

Engineer | Java Developer | Projects | Salesforce

Education

 Full Stack Developer (Backend Specialist) (Jun-2021 to Jun-2023)

Digital House

- Master in Business Administration (2001)
 Instituto Desarrollo Económico Argentino (IDEA)
- Electronics Engineering (1988 1995)
 Instituto Tecnológico de Buenos Aires (ITBA)

Courses & Certifications

 Event "Transforming Project Management: the role of AI" (May-2024)

DoInGlobal

- Agile Explorer (May-2024)
 IBM
- Explore Emerging Tech (May-2024)
 IBM
- PM4R Agile Innovation Projects (Jun-2023)

DoInGlobal - BID

Agile & Innovation Project Management

• Salesforce Admin (Apr-2023)

Silvertech - Tribo

Trailhead virtual bootcamp for new Admins

• School of Devops (Nov-2022)

Endava

Devops training

Linux, Docker, Scripting, Cloud Vendors, IaC, K8S

 Getting Started with AWS CloudFormation (Sep-2022)

AWS

 Excel: Create an intuitive and impactful dashboard from scratch (Jul-2020)

Linkedin

- Excel: Data Analysis (Jul-2020)
 Linkedin
- Excel: Enter data correctly (Jun-2020)
 Linkedin
- Excel: Pivot tables (Jun-2020)
 Linkedin
- Petroleum Measurements (2015)
 University of Texas Petroleum Extension Service

<u>Professional Experience</u>

Backend Developer - Digital Wallet Project Digital House

May 2023 - June 2023

Key responsibilities:

- Backend development using API Rest for a Digital Wallet Microservices Application
- Language: Java with SpringBoot
- Use of Keycloak for authorization and authentication (IAM)
- API documentation with Swagger
- Exceptions and Logging
- Relational database design (MySQL, Workbench)
- Manual and Automated Testing (Postman, JUnit, RestAssured)
- Infraestructure deploy with AWS services (EC2, S3, VPC)
- Shell scripting, Virtual Machines, Terraform, Docker, Kubernetes

Full Stack Developer - DigiRent Project Digital House

May 2022 - June 2022

Key responsibilities:

- Front-end development for a Rental Properties
 Web Application
- Web page design (FIGMA, responsive, accesibility)
- APIs integration (front-end and back-end)
- Back-end development (JAVA, Spring Boot, Maven)
- Entities, services, controllers, endpoints
- Exceptions and Logging (Log4J)
- Relational database design (MySQL, Workbench)
- Logical models (DER), entities, attributes, joins, queries.
- Manual and Automated Testing (Postman, Jest, Selenium)
- AWS services (EC2, S3, RDS, VPC)
- Shell scripting, Virtual Machines, Terraform, Docker

GUSTAVO LOBOS



Engineer | Java Developer | Projects | Salesforce

Work Experience

Downstream Oil&Gas Technical Consultant

April 2021 – April 2022

Key responsibilities:

- Operations and facilites Audits and Improvement
- Hydrocarbon Measurement Systems Audits
- · Oil Loss Analysis and Audits
- Measurement Practices Training
- Measurement Software Projects

Oil&Gas Operations and Projects (ESSO - Axionenergy - Pan American Energy)

1995 - 2020

Key responsibilities:

- Different positions and responsibilities (Terminals and Refinery).
- Process Design Specifications Engineering Projects Design.
- Project management (facilities, new technologies and upgrade, software implementation).
- Preparation of business cases for CAPEX projects. Presentations to stakeholders for approval. Follow up of project stages and collaboration with project and operations teams. Stakeholders presentations.
- Facilities operation and technical support (tanks, berth, lpg, loading racks, effluent treatment, coke pile and loading systems) and differente products handling.
- Safety and operational procedures implementation and review.
- Measurement operators training and certification. Training material design.
- Hydrocarbon Measurement and Oil Loss Specialist.
- International Standards (ISO 9001 and 14001, API MPSM, safety)
- · Global practices local implementation and support.
- Solution implementation for production accounting, balance, and data reconciliation applications (VMPA -KBC)

IT Helpdesk support ITS (onsite third party service in ESSO)

1994 - 1995

Key responsibilities:

- Software installations (DOS, Windows, custom apps)
- Internal users support Software troubleshooting
- Internal users support Hardware troubleshooting